Stablecoin payments have one problem
nobody talks about — they're final.
You pay, and if the merchant never
delivers, that's it. Your money's gone.
No chargeback. No recourse. That's the
wall between crypto and real commerce.
HSP fixed settlement — it made payments
verifiable and final.
Great for trust. But finality is exactly
what scares buyers off.
Look around this hackathon: everyone adds
control before money moves.
Approvals, KYC, spend limits. Nobody gives
you a way back after.
That's the lane Kembali owns.
And Kembali isn't just another escrow app —
it's a new primitive.
Deterministic, arbiter-free recourse.
Every other escrow needs someone to judge
whether delivery happened.
An oracle, a human, an AI arbiter, a bond
game. We removed all of it.
Because the deliverable lives on-chain,
"delivered" isn't an opinion —
it's a fact the contract checks itself.
Your payment sits in escrow, bound to an
on-chain deliverable and a deadline.
Merchant delivers the exact asset —
atomic swap, funds released.
Merchant doesn't — after the deadline,
your money comes back. Kembali.
Let me show you — all of this is live on
HashKey mainnet. Real transactions.
First the happy path: an atomic
delivery-versus-payment.
The buyer opens an escrow — one click
approves the stablecoin,
the next signs an EIP-712 HSP mandate
right in the wallet.
That signature's digest is the payment ID.
Funds are now held on-chain.
Now I switch to the merchant's wallet —
approve the deliverable, hit Fulfill.
In one transaction the asset goes to the
buyer and the funds release to the merchant.
No middleman ever touched it. Withdraw,
and the status reads RELEASED.
Now the part that matters — what if the
merchant never delivers?
Fresh escrow, short window. If the buyer
tries to refund now, it reverts.
TOO_EARLY. The buyer can't rug the merchant
mid-window — it's enforced on-chain.
We let the window pass, and now refund
goes through.
Buyer withdraws — status REFUNDED.
The money came back.
That's the recourse HSP alone
doesn't give you.
Next — agent-safe commerce.
This is the AI-meets-DeFi piece.
The escrow always pulls funds from whoever
signed the mandate — not whoever submits it.
So an agent, or a relayer, can place a buy
on your behalf and can't redirect a cent.
We proved it live: one wallet signs,
a different agent wallet submits,
and the funds come out of the signer.
The agent pays gas and nothing else.
An agent literally cannot rug you.
And for regulated settlement — HashKey's
whole thesis — compliance is on-chain.
CompliantEscrow checks the buyer's KYC and
sanctions attestations in an on-chain registry.
A hard require, before the escrow can even
open. No attestation, it reverts.
Not a checkbox in some backend — it's the
EVM saying no.
Compliant and reversible, both on-chain.
Under all of this is audit-grade
engineering.
Seventy-two tests, plus an invariant that
runs half a million random operations —
and proves the money can never leak.
Fifteen end-to-end tests drive this live
dApp with real mainnet transactions.
The canonical HSP payment ID is hashed and
verified on-chain, matching the reference SDK.
And the deployed bytecode is a byte-for-byte
match to the audited source. We checked.
Nothing here is a mock.
So that's Kembali. Everyone else built a
gate in front of the payment.
We built the door back out — trustlessly,
HSP-native, live on HashKey Chain.
Payments that can come back.